Guide to the Division of Nutritional Sciences Honors Theses, 1974-2015
Division of Nutritional Sciences Honors Theses, 1974-2015
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Division of Nutritional Sciences Honors Theses, 1974-2015
29-6-3419
.3 cubic feet.
Compact discs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Honors theses from the classes of 1974-2004 on CDs arranged by year.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Honors theses from the classes of 1974-2004 on CDs arranged by year.
SUBJECTS
Subjects:
Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University. Class of 1974.; Cornell University. Class of 1975.; Cornell University. Class of 1976.; Cornell University. Class of 1977.; Cornell University. Class of 1978.; Cornell University. Class of 1979.; Cornell University. Class of 1980.; Cornell University. Class of 1981.; Cornell University. Class of 1982.; Cornell University. Class of 1983.; Cornell University. Class of 1984.; Cornell University. Class of 1985.; Cornell University. Class of 1986.; Cornell University. Class of 1987.; Cornell University. Class of 1988.; Cornell University. Class of 1989.; Cornell University. Class of 1990.; Cornell University. Class of 1991.; Cornell University. Class of 1992.; Cornell University. Class of 1993.; Cornell University. Class of 1994.; Cornell University. Class of 1995.; Cornell University. Class of 1996.; Cornell University. Class of 1997.; Cornell University. Class of 1998.; Cornell University. Class of 1999.; Cornell University. Class of 2000.; Cornell University. Class of 2001.; Cornell University. Class of 2002.; Cornell University. Class of 2003.; Cornell University. Class of 2004.; Cornell University. Class of 2012.; Cornell University. Class of 2013.; Cornell University. Class of 2014.; Cornell University. Class of 2015.; Nutrition--Study and teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Folder numbers represent the number on the CD.
The DNS faculty voted not to retain the majority of Honors Theses created from 2005-2011.
Some honors theses are available online by clicking here.
Additional theses found New York State College of Human Ecology honors theses collection, #23-11-3264
SERIES LIST
Series I. 1974
Series II. 1975
Series III. 1976
Series VI. 1977
Series V. 1978
Series VI. 1979
Series VII. 1980
Series VIII. 1981
Series IX. 1982
Series X. 1983
Series XI. 1984
Series XII. 1985
Series XIII. 1986
Series XIV. 1988
Series XV. 1989
Series XVI. 1990
Series XVII. 1991
Series XVIII. 1993
Series XIX. 1994
Series XX. 1995
Series XXI. 1996
Series XXII. 1997
Series XXIII. 1998
Series XXIV. 1999
Series XXV. 2000
Series XXVI. 2001
Series XXVII. 2002
Series XXVIII. 2004
Series XXIX. 2012
Series XXX. 2013
Series XXXI. 2014
Series XXXII. 2015
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. 1974
  - Amy Cunningham: Cooking Measurement and Potential Metrication Among New York State Nutrition and Design Students, 1974, 2541
  - Lynne Anstendig Gordon: The Food Service Facility of Young Israel of Cornell, 1974, 2541
  - Michelle Lynn Falkenau: The Suitability of Plastic Containers in Microwave Ovens and the Effects of Shape, Volume, Heating Time, and the Use of Covers on Temperature and Temperature Distribution, 1974, 2541
- Series II. 1975
  - Janet Rosen: Interrelationship between Vitamins A and C on Adrenal Gland Activity, 1975, 2542
  - Laura Ann Davis: The Effect of Caloric Concentration and Gastric Emptying Time on Meal Patterns in Rats, 1975, 2542
  - Marjorie Brooks: Functional Properties and Acceptability of Egg Beaters and Other Similar Low Cholesterol Egg Products, 1975, 2542
  - Patricia Hayes: Nutritional Intake of Geriatric Patients at Lakeside Nursing Home, 1975, 2542
  - Randy Levine: The Effect that a Biguanide, Phenformin has on Vitamin B12 Status in the Rat, 1975, 2542
  - Susan Lustick: Metabolic Efficiency Changes Due to Overfeeding and Underfeeding in Female Albino Rats, 1975, 2542
  - Tay Secord: Opinions of Tompkins County Health Care Professionals on Nutrition During Pregnancy and Early Childhood and on Supplemental Feeding Programs, 1975, 2542
- Series III. 1976
  - Beth Goldstein: Methods for Quantitation for 7S and 11S IgA from Human Saliva, 1976, 2543
  - Carolyn Marie Schlede: The Effect of Nutritional Variables on Oxidative Sterol Demethylation, 1976, 2543
  - Catherine Feldman: Relationships Between Circulating Hemoglobin and Liver Iron in Adequately Nourished and Moderately Iron Deficient Growing Rats, 1976, 2543
  - Jill Lea Gyrisco: The Effect of Everyday Stress on Food Intake and Body Weight in a Sample of College Students, 1976, 2543
  - Karen Ann Roche: The Effect of Phenobarbital on the Folate Status of Chicks, 1976, 2543
  - Michele Marcia Brand: Measurement of Transit Time on Rats on Different Dietary Fiber Levels, 1976, 2543
  - Patricia Burden: The Effect of Diphenylhydantoin on the Folate Status of Chicks, 1976, 2543
- Series IV. 1977
  - Jane Fuchsberg: Parental Influence on the Reported and Observed Food Habits of Preschool Children, 1977, 2544
  - Karen Ann Kasnetz: The Contribution of Rich and Fortified Foods to Total Nutrient Intakes of Preschoolers, 1977, 2544
  - Martha Maso: The Effect of Developing Protein Deficiency on the MFO Enzyme System and Binding of AFB1 to Cellular Macromolecules, 1977, 2544
  - Michele Chan: A Preliminary Survey of the Food Habits of Chinese in Manhattan, New York, 1977, 2544
  - Paula Michelle Kessler: Food Additive Knowledge of Participants in Cooperative Extension Classes as Influenced by Nutrition Knowledge and Other Variables, 1977, 2544
  - Rochelle Rosenberg: Peer and Teacher Influence of the Observed Food Preferences of Preschool Children, 1977, 2544
  - Susan Solomon: The Effect of Zinc Deficiency on Detection Threshold of Quinine Sulfate in Rats, 1977, 2544
  - Wendy Gavin: Comparison of the Bioavailability of Natural and Enrichment Sources of Iron in Selected in Foods in Rats, 1977, 2544
- Series V. 1978
  - Daniel Small: Prenatal Growth at High Altitude: The Relationship of Iron Status to Birth Weight in Two Populations, 1978, 2545
  - Katherine Montana: Taste Sensitivity and Taste Preference for Sucrose in Preschoolers, 1978, 2545
  - Lori Ann Rothman: Effect of Various Binding Agents, Surfactants, and Added Ionizable Calcium Salt on the Structure and Palatability Characteristics of Shortened Cakes Prepared with Wheat Starch and with the Omission of Wheat Gluten, Eggs and Milk, 1978, 2545
  - Suzanne Tougas: The Effect of Zinc Deficiency on Prothrombin Time and Plasma Estrogen Levels of Pregnant Rats on Day 22 of Gestation, 1978, 2545
- Series VI. 1979
  - Judith Goldberg: Influence of Dietary Arginine and Potassium on Lysine Metabolism in High and Low Arginine Requiring Chickens, 1979, 2546
  - Judith Tomasso: The Effect of Linoleic Acid on Immune Function: A Pilot Study, 1979, 2546
  - Karen Gilmour: Oxalate Formation in Vitamin B-6 Deficient Mice Fed Xylitol, 1979, 2546
  - Kathleen Zappia: A Review of the Nutritional Profile and An Investigation of the Toxicity of Amaranthus Retroflexus, 1979, 2546
  - Leslee Roxanne Carver: Nutrition Knowledge of Preservice and Inservice Elementary School Teachers, 1979, 2546
  - Patrice Barsa: The Study of Pryidoxamine 5 - Phosphate Oxidase Activity in Rat Tissues During the Development of Riboflavin Deficiency and Pyridoxine Deficiency, 1979, 2546
- Series VII. 1980
  - Gwen Korovin: The Effect of Unsaturated Fatty Acid Addition in vitro on Red Blood Cell Osmotic Fragility, 1980, 2547
  - Janet Child: A Comparison of Salt Preference Behavior Among Elementary vs. High School Age Males, 1980, 2547
  - Linda Ripps: Relationships Between Nutrition Knowledge of Parents and Children, and the Quality of Home Packed Lunches as a Measure of Food Practices, 1980, 2547
  - Linda Goodman: The Effects of Tetracycline on the Riboflavin Status of Young Women, 1980, 2547
  - Linda Schaffer: The Effect of Carbohydrate Analogs on Glycolysis and Fructolysis in Bovine Spermatazoa, 1980, 2547
  - Merril Orenstein: Factors Influencing the Food Preferences of Preschoolers, 1980, 2547
  - Nancy Cohen: The Effect of Saccharin on Rat Liver Mixed Function Oxidase Activities and Aflatoxin B1 Distribution, 1980, 2547
- Series VIII. 1981
  - Carol Wolverton: Characterization of Thyroxine Binding Components in Bovine Liver Cytosol, 1981, 2548
  - Deborah Jeon: Functional Interrelationships of Containers and Food Loads in Microwave Heating, 1981, 2548
  - Elaine Tecklenburg: Consumers' Knowledge of Food Ingredients as Influenced by Selected Variables, 1981, 2548
  - Rhonda Shapiro: The Effect of Nutrition Education on Preschoolers' Food Preferences, 1981, 2548
  - Susan Manning: Comparison of Quality Attributes of Meat Patties After Cooking With and Without Browning Agents, 1981, 2548
  - Terri Larice Levin: The Effect of Housing Conditions on Hepatic Mixed Function Oxidase Activity and AFB1 Binding to Liver Macromolecules in Male Fisher Rats, 1981, 2548
- Series IX. 1982
  - Alice Trachtman: The Role Variability in the Diet Plays on Restrained and Unrestrained Eaters, 1982, 2549
  - Beth Berrous: The Possible Role of Torula Yeast in the Prevention of In Vivo Covalent Binding of Aflatoxin to Liver Macromolecules and Aflatoxin-Induced Preneoplastic Lesions in Laboratory Rats, 1982, 2549
  - Beth Reznik: Synthesis of Fructose Analogs and Their Effect on Gluconeogenesis in Rat Hepatocytes, 1982, 2549
  - Holly Flickinger: Long Term Effects on Exercise Cessation on Body Weight and Composition, 1982, 2549
  - Karen Daniels: The Effect of Dietary Cysteine Level on Cysteine Metabolism in Rats, 1982, 2549
  - Paul Gulick: Learning Styles and Learning Environment and Situation Preferences Among Nutrition Majors, 1982, 2549
  - Ronna Lynn Katz: could not open, 1982, 2549
  - Susan Elizabeth Staton: The Effect of Toasting on the Fiber Content on White and Whole Wheat Breads: Application of the Van Soest Detergent System, 1982, 2549
  - Teresa Schmitt: An Investigation of the Metabolic Alterations of Cancer, 1982, 2549
  - Veronica Guiry: The Relation of Caffeine Knowledge and Attitudes to Caffeine Consumption, 1982, 2549
- Series X. 1983
  - Barry Schlafstein: Modulation of the Thermogenic Effects Fenfluramine by Fat Adulterated Dietary Maintenance, 1983, 2550
  - Michele Kraver: Thiazide Induced Hyperglycemia a Predisposition?, 1983, 2550
  - Patricia Greene: The Thermogenic Interaction Between Nicotine and Nutrients, 1983, 2550
  - Scott Edward Blinkoff: Turkey Homogenates as Model Systems for Fatty Acid Autoxidation, 1983, 2550
- Series XI. 1984
  - Amy Shapiro: Effects of Diet Changes on Cornell Freshmen Women, 1984, 2551
  - Andrew Mark: The Effects of High Protein Feeding on the Activity of Glutaminase, Glutamate Dehydrogenase and Ornithine Transcarbamylase, in the Rat, 1984, 2551
  - Anne Parks: Choline and Cognition: The Effect of Exogenous Choline in the Rat, 1984, 2551
  - Elizabeth Joy Sprague: The Effect of Irrigation on Quality Factors of the Potato, 1984, 2551
  - Jeffrey Evan Gershenwald: Isolation and Characterization of Monoclonal Antibodies Against Avian Adipose Lipoprotein Lipase, 1984, 2551
  - John Barbaccia: The Effect of Administration of Oil of Evening Primrose on Urinary Prostaglandin F2a Levels in Zinc-Deficient Pregnant Rats Near Term, 1984, 2551
  - Julie Worden: Effect of Sex on Cysteine Sulfinate Decarboxylase Activity and Taurine Concentration in Liver and Brain of Young Rats and other Species, 1984, 2551
- Series XII. 1985
  - Cindi Arost: The Effects of Omega-Three Fatty Acids on Lipoprotein Metabolism in Roosters, 1985, 2552
  - Corinne Vanchieri: Study of the Long Term Effects of a Direct Mail Nutrition Education Program- A Telephone Survey, 1985, 2552
  - David Schulsinger: The Influence of Dietary Protein Quality During the Postdosing Phase on Aflatoxin B1- Induced Hepatic Preneoplastic Lesion Development in Rats, 1985, 2552
  - Jannette Travali: Studies of Glutamine Metabolism in Walker 256 Carcinomas, 1985, 2552
  - Jennifer Katz: Effects of Maternal High Altitude Exposure and Nutritional Status on Fetal and Placental Growth, 1985, 2552
  - Karen Lynn Field: Purification of Active Tyrosine Aminotransferase Using Immunoaffinity Chromatography, 1985, 2552
  - Patricia Nevins: In Vitro Determination of Zinc and Calcium Bioavailability with Varying Levels of Dietary Phytate and Fat, 1985, 2552
  - Stephen Mason: The Effects of Riboflavin and Alcohol on the Flavin Levels in the Hamster Kidney, 1985, 2552
  - Steven Kilburn: The Effect of In-Vitro Fatty Acid Incubation on Complement-Mediated Cell Lysis of Sheep Erythrocytes, 1985, 2552
- Series XIII. 1986
  - Christine Gleichauf: Effects of Maternal Malnutrition and Altitude Exposure During Childhood on Fetal and Placenta Growth, 1986, 2553
  - Cindy Davis: The Phosphotransferase Activity of Glucose-6-Phosphatase in Intact Hepatocytes Using (3H)3-0-methyl-D-glucose as a Substrate, 1986, 2553
  - Dorothy Poshadel: Zinc Uptake in Zinc Adequate and Marginally Zinc Deficient Pregnant Rats and Their Fetuses, 1986, 2553
  - Karen Susan Lazan: An Investigation of the Causes of Reduced Litter Number in Chronically Malnourished Rats, 1986, 2553
  - Mary Rinko: The Compliance of Residents of the Oxford's Veterans' Home with Therapeutic Dietary Regimens, 1986, 2553
  - Shobhina Girish Chheda: Matabolism of Cysteine and Cysteinesulfinate in Isolated Kidney Tubules from the Rat, 1986, 2553
- Series XIV. 1988
  - Bradford David Ress: The Effects of Fatty Acids on Human T Lymphocytes, 1988, 2554
  - Caitlin Hosmer: Suppression of Energy Intake in Rat by Dietary Fibers, 1988, 2554
  - Christy Brown: Role of Riboflavin in Drug-Induced Photohemolysis, 1988, 2554
  - Gayle Frazzetta: The Effects of High Levels of Dietary Vitamin E on Atherogenesis in Quails, 1988, 2554
  - Howard Ross: Intestinal Threonine Accumulation in Theronine Imbalanced Chicks, 1988, 2554
  - Jennifer Arent: Validation of a Revised Protocol for Assessing Erythrocyte Protoporphyrins for Field Studies of Iron Deficiency, 1988, 2554
  - Karen Lindner: Acute Effects of Calcium Carbonate and Dairy Calcium on Absorption of Riboflavin, 1988, 2554
- Series XV. 1989
  - Eleanor Krieger: The Modulation of Aflatoxin B1 Induced Preneoplastic Lesions by Dietary Protein and Voluntary Exercise in Fischer-344 Rats, 1989, 2555
  - Jacqueline Evette Ehrlich: Cause for the Negative Cis Effect on E1B Transcription Induced by the Insertion by the Mouse B-Globin Terminator Element into the E1A Gene of Adenovirus, 1989, 2555
  - Richard Scott Safeer: Inhibition of Calcium-ATPase Activity by Enzymatic Glycosylation, 1989, 2555
  - Susan Psaila: A Comparative Study of the Assessment of Lean Body Mass in Anorexia Nervosa Patients Using 40K Whole Body Counting and Bioelectrical Impedance, 1989, 2555
- Series XVI. 1990
  - Heidi Weinroth: The Chronic Effects of Fenpluramine and Diet on the Energy Expenditure and Body Composition of the Rat, 1990, 2556
- Series XVII. 1991
  - Janet Yi-jen Chen:United States Nutrition Policy Regarding Dietary Prevention of Coronary Heart Disease, 1991, 2557
  - Katherine Alaimo: The Role of Meat in Early Hominid Diets, 1991, 2557
  - Sheli Bodnar: Differences in Body Composition Between Women of European and African Descent, 1991, 2557
- Series XVIII. 1993
  - Esther Kim: Food Consumption Patterns and Factors Affecting Food Choices and their Relationship to Vegetarianism, Dieting Status, and Body Mass Index in Female College Students, 1993, 2558
  - Gavin Neil Somersel: Mutations Within a Potential CIS Regulatory Element in C-ABL Oncogene Reduces the Binding of Potential Trans-Regulatory Elements, 1993, 2558
  - Jamie Gottlieb: Methylphenidate: A Possible Approach to the Management of Juvenile Obesity, 1993, 2558
  - Paul Michael Sethi: The Regulation of Hepatic Metallothionein mRNA Concentrations During Fasting: Evidence for Post Transcriptional Control, 1993, 2558
  - Staci Mayer: A Multivariate Analysis of Psychological Variables and Eating Behavior in Undergraduate Women, 1993, 2558
- Series XIX. 1994
  - Edward Leonard: Weight Control Practices of High School Wrestlers, 1994, 2559
  - Mary Kuo: Factors that Influence the Food Consumption and Nutritional Status of Young Females in College, 1994, 2559
  - Michael Robert Cummings: Factors Involved with Food Choice Behavior and Dietary Intake of College Males 18-24 Years of Age with Regard to Living Situation, 1994, 2559
  - Michelle Banducci: The Thin Ideal and Changes in Women's Roles, 1994, 2559
  - Renee Un Hye Choe: Studies to Examine the Interaction Between the Chlorogenic Acid Analogue, S0838 and the Transporter Component of the Glucose-6-Phosphatase System, 1994, 2559
  - Suzanne Perks: The Infant Pig as a Model for Iron Bioavailability to Humans, 1994, 2559
  - Yasmeen Kutty: The Effect of the Consumption of a High Fat Diet on Reproduction in Sprague-Dawley Rats, 1994, 2559
- Series XX. 1995
  - David Fitzgerald: The Nursing Method of Mild Extraction Can be Used to Compare Mild from Well and Poorly Nourished Animals, 1995, 2560
  - Hillary Raffman: The Effects of Low Level Developmental Lead Exposure on Long Term Declarative Memory on Rats, 1995, 2560
  - Maureen Alexandra Shaw: The Consumption of a High-Fat Diet Reduces Reproductive Performance in Rats, 1995, 2560
  - Tara Kim Sotsky: Impact of Religious Dietary Laws on Food Attitudes and Choices: How and Why Are Jews Keeping Kosher?, 1995, 2560
- Series XXI. 1996
  - Anne Kayani: Desaturation of Stearate and Palmitate in Humans Using a Stable Isotope Label, 1996, 2561
  - Bettina Lippert: The Availability, Price, and Quality of Fruits and Vegetables in a Low-Income Area of Rochester, New York, 1996, 2561
  - Jessica Fehringer: Postpartum Weight Retention: Relationship to Employment and Employment Characteristics, 1996, 2561
  - Jessica Hills: Effects of 5-Formyltetrahydrofolate Accumulation on Folate-Dependent One-Carbon Metabolism, 1996, 2561
  - Laura Treye Weissman: Documentation of a Second-by-Second Breastfeeding Using a Novel Method, 1996, 2561
  - Margaret Anne MacMillan: A Multicomponent Model for the Estimation of Body Composition Using Anthropometry and Bioelectrical Impedance, 1996, 2561
  - Marion Vetter: An Examination of Lectin Content in Chenopodium Quinoa, 1996, 2561
  - Michelle Shah: Food Practices of Indian American Students: Exploring Dimensions of Ethnicity in Food Choice, 1996, 2561
  - Neera Gupta: Comparison of the Fatty Acid Profiles of Maternal and Fetal Ovine Retina Phospholipids, 1996, 2561
  - Wendy Irwin: Health Care Surrogates and the Decision to Tube Feed, 1996, 2561
- Series XXII. 1997
  - Christopher Michael Matsko: The Effects of Maternal Food Deprivation During Placental Growth on Fetal Organ Weight and Fatty Acid Consumption, 1997, 2562
  - David Bauer: Ability to Taste 6-n-propylthiouracil and the Perception of Food Tastiness, 1997, 2562
  - Gavin Schwartz: A Preliminary Evaluation of Two Methods for Determining Total Dietary Fiber Content of Human Foods, 1997, 2562
  - Jennifer Sheldon: Nutrition Education in the WIC Program: Does it Make a Difference?, 1997, 2562
  - Kerry Eby: Food Consumption Frequency and Nutrient Intake, 1997, 2562
  - Linda Monia Dini: Association Between Being Breast-Fed and Body Mass Index in Sample of White, Rural Dwelling High School Students, 1997, 2562
  - Rachel Fremder: The Influences on College Women's Exercise Behavior, 1997, 2562
  - Sarrie Feldman: The Breakfast Study: Determinants of Eating Behavior, 1997, 2562
- Series XXIII. 1998
  - Diana Goldenberg: The Protective Effect of Breastfeeding Against Common Illnesses in Infancy, 1998, 2563
  - Eden Renee Rauch: Ovine Fetal Hypothalamic-Pituitary-Adrenal-Placental Axis Responses to Hypoxia After Repetitive Placental Embolization, 1998, 2563
  - Elizabeth Bowdish: Conceptualizations of Seasonal and Local Foods, 1998, 2563
  - Jacqueline Cohen: Consideration of the Role of Iron Status in the Prediction of VO2max of Young Women, 1998, 2563
  - Melissa Nelson: The Vitamin V6 Status of Children with Sickle Cell Disease and its Relation to Disease Severity, Growth and Development, 1998, 2563
  - Monica Calero: Effect of Hypoxia on the Synthesis of Nitric Oxide by Macrophages: Kinetic Analysis of Arginine Requirement, 1998, 2563
  - Rikin Patel: Relationship of Hedonic Ratings of Different Sucrose Concentrations to Food Consumption Frequency, 1998, 2563
- Series XXIV. 1999
  - Alyssa Feinman: Vegetarians' and Nonvegetarians' Perceptions of the Potential Nutritional Inadequacies of a Lacto-ovo Vegetarian Diet, 1999, 2564
  - Clarie Ryan: Usability of a Regional Food Guide Among WIC Participants, 1999, 2564
  - Davie Levinthal: The Role of Cellular Retinoic Acid Binding Proteins in the Intracellular Transport of Retinoic Acid, 1999, 2564
  - Erin O'Hare: Dance and Nutrition: A Review of the Literature and Analysis of Dance, Diet and Performance, 1999, 2564
  - Jennifer Amengual: Good News for Dieters: Imprecise Control of Food Intake, 1999, 2564
  - Jennifer Sheldon: An Analysis of Nutrient Intakes Among Nutrient Supplement Users and Nonusers in the Food Stamp Population, 1999, 2564
  - Karen Hye-cheon Kim: Testing Echinacea's Effect on the Common Cold Through Electronic Mail, 1999, 2564
  - Kathryn Lynn Carlson: The Interrelationship Between Vitamin A Deficiency and Anemia: Evidence for Simultaneous Deficiencies and Predictors of Benefit in a Randomized Trial of a Multiple Micronutrient Fortified Beverage Among School Children in Tanzania, 1999, 2564
  - Mary Lynn Tan: A Forecast of Malnutrition by Regional Experts, 1999, 2564
  - Meridith Bogart: Self Presentation of Body Weight and Food Identities in Personal Advertisements, 1999, 2564
  - Sara Elizabeth Best: A Study of the Eating Patterns, Menstrual Cycle, and Exercise Habits in Females, 1999, 2564
- Series XXV. 2000
  - Christine Yu: A Qualitative Comparison of Three Methods of Analyzing Total Antioxidant Activity in Cereals and Pseudo-Cereal Grains, 2000, 2565
  - Doreen Faye Toskos: She Ate That? Management of the Social Aspects of Eating Among Female University Students, 2000, 2565
  - Elizabeth Hill: Structural and Physico-Chemical Properties of Buckwheat Startch, 2000, 2565
  - Evan Berk: The Relationship Between Olfactory Function, Gender and Use of Oral Contraceptives: A Pilot Study, 2000, 2565
  - Jacob Pacos: The Role of Cellular Retinoic Acid Binding Protein II in Retinoic Acid-Induced Cell Differentiation, 2000, 2565
  - Jane Kang: The unexpected Increase in Leptin Protein Production Following Leptin Antisense Treatment of 373-F442A Cells, 2000, 2565
  - Jennifer Radi: The Responsiveness of Women to the Educational Intervention of the Bassett Mothers Health Project II, 2000, 2565
  - Khaliah Aesha Johnson: The Qualitative Examiniation of Infant Feeding Beliefs and Practices in Kalimani, Kitui, Kenya, 2000, 2565
  - Laura Baber: An Observational Study of Family Interactions in Farmers' Markets in Upstate New York, 2000, 2565
  - Manny Porat: Effect of Steroid Hormones on Endothelin Induced Responses in Myometrium of Non-Pregnant Ovarectomized Sheep, 2000, 2565
  - RL Bruckner: Gendar Differences in Peripheral Color Vision, 2000, 2565
  - Shari Goldfarb: The Effects of Gender, Diet and Lifestyle Factors on Iron Status of College Students, 2000, 2565
  - Shilpa Londhe: A Study of the Constraints on Ethical Decision Making: A New Approach to the End-Of-Life Care Healthcare System, 2000, 2565
  - Trent Stellingwerff: Characterization of a Hepatocyte Cell Culture Model for Studying Metabolism of y-Tocopherol to Water-Soluble Metabolites, 2000, 2565
- Series XVI. 2001
  - Abiola Dele-Michael: Is Poor Medication Adherence Rational Behavior Among African-American Hypertensives?, 2001, 2566
  - Andrew Yee: The Role of Prostrate Specific Antigen Density and Prostrate Specific Velocity in Predicting Organ Confined Disease and Seminal Vesicle Involvement, 2001, 2566